I'll calculate the average of these numbers by adding them up and dividing by three.
سأحسب متوسط تلك الأرقام عن طريق جمعها وقسمتها على ثلاثة.
I'll use the print function to see the result.
سأستخدم دالة الطباعة لملاحظة النتيجة.
Hmm.
ها.
This is not what I expected. It's an error message.
هذا ليس ما كنت أتوقعه. إنها رسالة خطأ.
It's a bit disappointing,
هذا مخيب للآمال بعض الشيء.
but hopefully the error message will explain the issue.
لكن نأمل أن رسالة الخطأ ستوضح المشكلة.
The bottom line says that I made
يشير الخط السفلي أنني ارتكبت خطأ في بناء الجملة
a syntax error and the caret points to the relevant line of the code.
ونقاط علامة الإقحام في خط الكود ذو الصلة.
So, it looks like I made a typo and left out the first parenthesis in the call to print.
لذا، يبدو أنني ارتكبت خطأ مطبعيًا ونسيت القوس الأول عند استدعاء دالة الطباعة
I'll fix it and try again.
سأصلح الأمر وأحاول مجددًا.
OK, good. It worked this time.
&gt;&gt; حسنًا، جيد لقد نجحت هذه المرة.
Great. Fortunately, this error message was pretty straightforward.
هذا رائع. لحسن الحظ، كانت رسالة الخطأ واضحة للغاية.
This won't always be the case though.
لن يكون الحال هكذا دائمًا.
Sometimes you'll get errors that are more difficult to read.
في بعض الأحيان، ستحصلون على رسائل خطأ يصعُب قراءتها.
They can still be helpful though.
ولكنها رغم ذلك تكون مفيدة للغاية.
If you get an error that you don't understand,
إذا حصلتم على رسالة خطأ، وتعذر عليكم فهمها،
copy it into a search engine to get more information about what has happened.
قوموا بنسخها إلى محرك البحث وستحصلون على معلومات عما يحدث.